<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The English people-a problem, as all philos-.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>The Times (London, England). Thursday, Jul 09, 1857; pg. 8; Issue 22728.</p>
         </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Gale Document Number: CS134910185</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <ab>using decimal code \#8212; for em dashes</ab>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <p><s><w type="noun" subtype="indirectobj">The English people</w>&#8212;<w type="noun" subtype="dirobj">a problem</w>, as all <w type="noun" subtype="subject">philosophers</w> <w type="verb" subtype="transitive" lemma="call">call</w> them&#8212;offer at
                  this moment a spectacle more than usually singular and characteristic.</s>
               <s>Is it a just confidence in our character and position, or is it an ignorant
                  rashness, which makes so many of us look for the arrival of the next news from
                  <location source="1269750"><country>India</country></location>, now expected every day,&#8212;in three or four days at the
                  latest,&#8212;with about as much interest as we should an overdue Australian
                  steamer or the result of a rising at <location source="3117735"><placeName>Madrid</placeName></location>? They, indeed, who have friends in
                  <location source="1269750"><country>India</country></location> have their own anxieties and speculations, for the Mail which may announce
                  the entire supression of the mutiny may bring all the cost of valuable lives at
                  which it has been purchased.</s>
               <s>But the British public, as a whole, looks and talks as if many a like danger had
                  vanished as soon as known, and as if our good fortune or invincible courage must
                  carry us as easily through a Sepoy mutiny.</s>
               <s>Yet what is the fact, and how does that fact address itself to the geographical
                  ideas of our continental neighbours? The fact is a growing dissatisfaction and a
                  sudden mutiny, long lurking and eventually breaking out for the length of a
                  thousand miles across the <location source="1269750"><placeName>whole Peninsula</placeName></location>, suppressed with cautious tact and a
                  great display of force at <location source="1275004"><placeName>Calcutta</placeName></location> and in <location source="1259224"><placeName>the Punjab</placeName></location>, but triumphant so far at the
                  ancient capital of the Mogul Empire, the prophetic seat of power.</s>
               <s>This is the state of things in a territory where less than 50,000 Europeans of all
                  kinds hold in subjection seven times their number of armed men and a population of
                  170,000,000.</s>
               <s>The meshes of such a fabric cannot be very close.</s>
               <s>The stations must be very wide apart, the communications difficult and slow, the
                  detachments must be numerous and small; the travellers many, and but feebly
                  escorted.</s>
               <s>Nothing but <emph>prestige</emph>, a word so often applied to Indian affairs as to
                  have become an Orientalism, can give strength to so flimsy a web and lull the
                  tempest that, once raised, would sweep away every thread of it.</s>
               <s>Think how many French troops are necessary in <location source="2589581/"><country>Algeria</country></location>, scarcely out of sight of
                  their native shores, and along a thin coast! Yet, if the Hindoos are not generally
                  a war-like race, there are still mixed up with them, and forming the best part of
                  the native army, numberous races much stronger and more ambitious.</s>
               <s>We deal with the descendants of conquerors; with those who still inherit titles of
                  sovereignty; with hardy mountaineers; with recent marauders; with men whose very
                  strength and savageness made it politic to enlist them.</s>
               <s>The scene of the long smouldering discontent and the sudden outbreak is a
                  vast country, much of which is little known, but where conspiracy lurks in
                  populations created by ourselves, and preaks out at the very head-quarters of our
                  dominion.</s>
               <s>Such are the hard facts of the case, and bystanders who look at the hard facts
                  must marvel at our composure.</s></p>
            <p><s>But, after all, this is not the blind faith in a destiny or the rash confidence in
                  our arms that a bystander might suppose.</s>
               <s>We know the danger, and calculate it.</s>
               <s>We know what the next Mail may possibly bring, and we have also our estimate.</s>
               <s>When General ANSON concentrates his forces on <location source="1273294"><placeName>Delhi</placeName></location>, which at the last date seemed
                  only a matter of time, and of a very short time, it is a question whether the
                  insurgents will attempt to hold the city at the risk of entire destruction, or
                  follow their own more natural tastes, as well as the safer course, by breaking up
                  and scattering themselves over the country.</s>
               <s>In the formering case, without leaders, wihtout artillery, ammuition, or stores,
                  within a wide circle of ancient walls, and with no power of defending any one part
                  of the city without sacrificing the rest, they must soon surrender at discretion,
                  or abide the terrible issue of an assault.</s>
               <s>No doubt, they reckon somewhat on the name of the city and on the fanatical
                  character of the Mahomedan population.</s>
               <s>They may, too, expect that a little perseverane may win support from the
                  neighbouring States, whose fidelity we cannot reckon upon in the case of a
                  reverse.</s>
               <s>But to this course we see only one result, in which the treatment of the Mogul
                  capital must be determined by military and political considerations.</s>
               <s>Should the insurgents anticipate the siege by flight, then no doubt, they will
                  give us much trouble of a harassing, but less serious, character.</s>
               <s>But we have already seen how they have been received in their flight by those
                  native chiefs to whose sympathy they appealed in an hour of temporary success.</s>
               <s>As fugitives they will nowhere be able to make head against us.</s>
               <s>The example of their dispersion must tell everywhere; and whatever credit has
                  attached to the possession of <location source="1273294"><placeName>Delhi</placeName></location> must redound the disgrace of their cause.</s>
               <s>This disposes of the two great alternatives before us.</s> <s>In either case,
               however, we must still prepare our minds for lamentable events at other places than
                  <location source="1273294"><placeName>Delhi</placeName></location>.</s>
               <s>There is too much reason to fear that European officers at the smaller stations,
                  or travelling perhaps in ignorance of these events, may be surprised by assassins
                  or by excited crowds,&#8212;possibly by the dispersed mutineers.</s>
               <s>The number of such casualties will partly depend on the interval allowed to pass
                  between the first outbreak and the final retribution.</s>
               <s>Therefore it is of the utmost importance that the latter should be as speedy and
                  signal as the strength and disposition of the army will allow.</s>
               <s>Every day that leaves <location source="1273294"><placeName>Delhi</placeName></location> in the hands of the men who have massacred the British
                  population,&#8212;every day that sees them unpunished, will certainly add to the
                  list of European victims.</s></p>
            <p><s>The Sepoys have not yet stood their ground anywhere, for one minute, against so
                  much as a company or a troop of European soldiers.</s>
               <s>They have only surprised and murdered officers while addressing them, or even
                  unconscious of danger.</s>
               <s>Of course, it is not to be inferred that they will never stand their ground under
                  resolute officers or when urged by desperation.</s>
               <s>They may, as other semi-barbarians have been before them, be encouraged to a
                  formidable degree of self-confidence by the fatal blunders or unavoidable
                  disasters of the Europeans.</s>
               <s>But this can only be a transient delusion, and there can be no doubt the lesson
                  which the Sepoys have already received will be repeated with increasing force, and
                  be the last left on their minds.</s>
               <s>This certainly suggests some serious considerations as to the relations to be
                  observed for the future between the numbers of the European and the native
                  army.</s>
               <s>Long ago, on he cessation of the late wars, experienced British officers were
                  strongly in favour of the reduction, not of the number of native regiments to
                  their full complement.</s>
               <s>Now, to what extent it is possible to raise the number of European soldiers in
                  <location source="1269750"><country>India</country></location>, now under 50,000, or how it may also be possible to reduce the native army,
                  may be a nice and difficult question.</s>
               <s>But the brief history of this lamentable outbreak shows the strength of a small
                  European force, and the danger, as well as the weakness, of a large Indian
                  one.</s>
               <s>The self-confidence naturally engendered among a lare body of armed natives
                  considerably under-officered has certainly contributed much to disaffection and
                  mutiny.</s>
               <s>Other causes may also have had their share.</s>
               <s>There may be too great a distance between the native soldier and the British
                  officer.</s>
               <s>The latter may have allowed the native officer to overstep his rank.</s>
               <s>There may have been a criminal neglect of the native superstitions.</s>
               <s>The causes may have hastened, aggravated, and excused the outbreak.</s>
               <s>But at the bottom of the whole is the sense of subjection, and the reliance on
                  numbers ot shake it off.</s>
               <s>This feeling will exist under the best management, and survive when policy has
                  done its best.</s>
               <s>We must therefore always be on our guard against it, and take care to keep the
                  balance of power in European hands.</s></p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
